[
  {
    "question": "After implantation, finger-like projections appear on the trophoblast called ______.",
    "answer": "chorionic villi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Chorionic villi are surrounded by ______ and maternal blood.",
    "answer": "uterine tissue"
  },
  {
    "question": "The chorionic villi and uterine tissue jointly form a structural and functional unit called ______.",
    "answer": "placenta"
  },
  {
    "question": "The placenta facilitates the supply of ______ and nutrients to the embryo.",
    "answer": "oxygen"
  },
  {
    "question": "The placenta also removes ______ and excretory/waste materials produced by the embryo.",
    "answer": "carbon dioxide"
  },
  {
    "question": "The placenta is connected to the embryo through an ______ which helps in transport of substances.",
    "answer": "umbilical cord"
  },
  {
    "question": "Placenta acts as an endocrine tissue and produces hormones like ______, hPL, estrogens, and progestogens.",
    "answer": "hCG"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the later phase of pregnancy, the hormone ______ is secreted by the ovary.",
    "answer": "relaxin"
  },
  {
    "question": "hCG, hPL and relaxin are produced in women only during ______.",
    "answer": "pregnancy"
  },
  {
    "question": "During pregnancy, levels of hormones like estrogens, progestogens, cortisol, prolactin, and ______ increase several-folds in maternal blood.",
    "answer": "thyroxine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Increased production of these hormones supports fetal growth, metabolic changes in the mother, and ______ of pregnancy.",
    "answer": "maintenance"
  }
]
